okay so now that we have seen two types
of dependencies and how can they affect
the scheduling of instructions in a
process that is trying to do more than
an instruction per cycle let's do a
dependency quiz let's say we have a
processor with a classical five stage
pipeline meaning that in one cycle it
fetches then reads registers and decodes
and executes then performs a memory
access and finally writes registers
let's also say that the processor has
forwarding that can if the result has
been produced it's gonna feed it to the
instruction correctly even though maybe
the result has not been written to a
register yet but the result has to have
been produced meaning that the
instruction that produces the result had
to either finish the execute stage if
the result is something like a plus or
had to finish the memory stage if this
is a load instruction so we can
basically then feed that result to the
instruction that executes in the next
cycle without having to wait for the
producing instruction to get to the
right register stage just as we
discussed before and finally let's say
that this processor can execute ten
instructions in its stage so
theoretically it could in one cycle
fetch ten instructions then the Codel
ten then execute all ten if there are no
dependencies and so on so in five cycles
is going to execute all ten instructions
if we have 20 instructions the first ten
will be fetch in the first cycle
it would immediately in the next cycle
fetch the next and so theoretically it
would be able to finish all 20 in six
cycles because we have to still get to
the right track stage the question is
when do we execute and write back each
of these instructions so we have these
six instructions and the question is
when do we execute and to help you get
started let's say that the very first
cyclic cycles zero that is when we fetch
them all
it reads registers in cycle 1 so it will
execute definitely in cycle 2 also
because the add here is using r2 it has
to wait for the mode to execute and then
forwarding will produce the most value
to the add so the add has to wait an
execute in cycle 3 if you look at the
mouse because it has executed in cycle 2
it will go through the main stage in
cycle 3 and write its result in cycle 4
the question is
when are these others in what cycles are
they producing and writing their results